Himanshu Gunwant

himanshu-gunwant.com linkedin.com/in/himanshu-gunwant github.com/monster-anshu

Full Stack Developer

Possessing 2 years of experience in utilizing modern frameworks and libraries such as React.js, Next.js, Node.js, MongoDB, and Redux. Demonstrated proficiency in successfully delivering over 7 scalable projects, consistently ensuring alignment with user requirements and exceeding expectations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, PHP, Java, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Go Lang

Frameworks: React.js, Express, Node.js, Next.js, React Native, TailwindCSS, Serverless, NestJS

Libraries : Material, Redux Toolkit, React Router, React Query

Databases : MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, DynamoDB

Devops : AWS, Github, Docker, Jenkins, Vercel

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Acefone Softwares

Software Development Engineer 2

August 2024 – Present

Email: hgunwant2312@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 7505064723

Gurugram

• Microservice architecture to reduce overhead of main application by 85%.

- Pub Sub System with Kafka.
- PHP and Laravel for admin panel.
- Microfrontend using ReactJS and NextJS.
- Built telephonic system with Asterisk PBX.

Software Development Engineer

September 2022 – August 2024

Orufy Technologies Jaipur

- Monorepo setup with Turborepo and Nx for 4+ projects.
- Bot builder with **React flow** to design bot 70% faster.
- Led a team of 5 developers.
- Engineered a drag-and-drop email template builder with **GrapesJS**, reducing design time by 40% and increasing engagement rates by 25%.
- Architected and deployed 5+ scalable projects with React.js, Next.js, NextJS, and Node.js.
- Built backend with server and Serverless Environments with AWS Lambdas.
- Developed 4+ plugins for **Shopify** and **Wordpress** applications.

React.js Developer

Fintricity

January 2022 – August 2022

Remote - London

- Created a Component Library with **Storybook** for 20+ reusable components.
- Converted a 20,000+ line JavaScript codebase to TypeScript, improving developer experience and error detection by 30%.
- Implemented 10+ data visualizations using the ReCharts library.
- Collaborated with a team of 7 developers to enhance project efficiency.
- Optimized application performance, resulting in a 20% increase in speed.

EDUCATION

Dev Bhoomi Uttarakhand Univeristy

Bachelor of Computer Application

Dehradun, Uttarakhand 2020 – 2023

Vivekanand Intermediate College

Intermediate

Almora, Uttarakhand 2020

PROJECTS

Webtonative

- Convert website to app without code.
- Integrated payment gateways for seamless payments, handling 5K+ transactions monthly.
- 50K+ active international clients.
- Next.js, TypeScript, Firebase, and Node.js for development.

E-Commerce Site

- Responsive E Commerce website clone using Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS and Redux Toolkit.
- Implemented authentication using NextAuth.
- Added user delivery location feature using Geolocation-DB API.
- Created CI/CD pipeline with GitHub and Vercel for automation.

Snappy - Chat App

- Front-end using React.js, styled-components, Typescript .
- Backend with **Node.js**, **Express** and **MongoDB**.
- Stabilized web socket connection with **socket.io**, achieving 99.9% uptime.

GIF Maker Source Code

- Developed a gif maker web app using **React.js**.
- Backend with Node.js, Express and MongoDB.
- Used Web assembly and FFmpeg for video processing.
- 100% processing on web browser.

Interests

- Crafting innovative Web and Mobile Applications
- Actively Contributing to Open Source Projects to foster community growth
- Exploring the potentials of Machine Learning with Python for real-world applications